Guide to the Ann Lauterbach Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Ann Lauterbach papers
1926-2000
YCAL MSS 736
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
31.88
(29 boxes)
The Ann Lauterbach Papers document the personal and professional life of American poet Ann Lauterbach and consist of correspondence, writings, printed material, and audiovisual material. The papers contain a number of drafts of Lauterbach's writings from early in her career until roughly 2000. Her correspondence reflects her intellectual circle with correspondents including writers and artists: Stacy Doris, Kenward Gray Elmslie, Richard Hamilton, Susan Howe, Garrett Kalleberg, Ron Padgett, Peter Straub, Marjorie Welish, and Chet Wiener. The papers also contain material relating to Lauterbach's family members including her father, war correspondent Richard Lauterbach.
Lauterbach, Ann, 1942-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from George Robert Minkoff Inc. on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 2001, and Granary Books, Inc. on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 19, 29 (audio and videocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Ann Lauterbach (1942- )
American poet Ann Lauterbach was born on September 28, 1942, in New York City to Richard Edward (a war correspondent) and Elisabeth Stuart Wardewell Lauterbach. She graduated from the High School of Music and Art in New York City and then obtained a Bachelor of Arts from the University of Wisconsin in 1964. She attended Columbia University on a Woodrow Wilson graduate fellowship from 1966 to 1967.
Following her studies, Lauterbach moved to London, England, where she served as an editor for Thames & Hudson Publishers (1967-1973) and taught at Saint Martin's School of Art (1967-1973). During this time Lauterbach was also director of the literature program at the Institute of Contemporary Art. While living in England Lauterbach published her first book of poetry: Vertical, Horizontal (Dublin, Ireland: Seafront Press, 1971).
Lauterbach returned to New York City where she was employed as an art consultant for various galleries (1974-1984) and as the assistant director of the Washburn Gallery (1984-1986). Lauterbach has maintained a career teaching creative writing concurrently with writing and publishing her poetry. She served as a professor of creative writing at various universities, including Brooklyn College (1985-1986), City College, City University of New York, (1989-1998), and the Graduate Center of the University of New York (1993). In 1991 Lauterbach joined the M.F.A. writing faculty at Bard College.
Her poetry publications include: Book One (Spring Street Press: New York, NY, 1975), Clamor (Viking: New York, NY, 1991), And for Example (Viking: New York, NY, 1994), and Or to Begin Again (Penguin Books: New York, NY, 2009). Lauterbach also published Greeks with Bruce Boice (Hollow Press: Baltimore, MD, 1985) and an essay The Night Sky: Writings on the Poetics of Experience (Viking: New York, NY, 2005). She has contributed to a number of periodicals including American Letters and Commentary, American Poetry Review, Artforum, and Denver Quarterly.
Scope and Contents
The Ann Lauterbach Papers document the personal and professional life of American poet Ann Lauterbach and consist of correspondence, writings, printed material, and audiovisual material.
Lauterbach's creative life is reflected in her writings and correspondence. The papers contain a number of drafts of Lauterbach's writings from early in her career until roughly 2000. Her correspondence reflects her intellectual circle with correspondents including a number of writers and artists: Stacy Doris, Kenward Gray Elmslie, Richard Hamilton, Susan Howe, Garrett Kalleberg, Ron Padgett, Peter Straub, Marjorie Welish, and Chet Wiener. The papers also contain other authors' manuscripts submitted to Lauterbach for review.
In addition, the papers relate to Lauterbach's personal life. Included in the papers are journals and yearly planners dating from the 1960s to the 1990s. Lauterbach's correspondence with family members, namely her mother (Elizabeth Lauterbach) and sister (Jennifer Lauterbach), similarly provide insight into her life. The papers also include a journal belonging to her father Richard Lauterbach.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: I. February 2001 Acquisition, 1926-1999. II. May 2007 Acquisition, 1970-2000.
American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors and publishers; Poets, American -- New York (State); Women authors; Audiocassettes -- United States -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Doris, Stacy; Elmslie, Kenward, 1929-; Hamilton, Richard, 1922-2011; Howe, Susan, 1937-; Kalleberg, Garrett; Lauterbach, Ann, 1942-; Lauterbach, Richard E. (Richard Edward), 1914-1950; Padgett, Ron, 1942-; Straub, Peter, 1943-; Welish, Marjorie, 1944-; Wiener, Chet
- I. February 2001 Acquisition, 1926-1999; 24.38; (21 boxes)
  Arrangement
  February 2001 Acquisition is organized into seven groupings: Correspondence, Poetry, Prose, Journals, Early Writing, Ephemera, and Oversize.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains: correspondence, writings, printed material, and audiovisual material by or relating to Ann Lauterbach. Includes Greeks drafts and proofs.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 109.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 19 (audiocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Correspondence
    - Allen, Duff, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Altieri, Charles, 1989-96; 3 (Box 1)
    - Andrews, Bruce, 1994-96 (Box 1)
    - Ashbery, John, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Auster, Paul, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Barrett, Edward, 1986-99; 3 (Box 1)
    - Batterham, David, undated (Box 1)
    - Bauer, Douglas, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Beachy-Quick, Dan, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Bellen, Martine, 1994-95 (Box 1)
    - Bernstein, Charles, 1989-94 (Box 1)
    - Berssenbrugge, Mei-Mei, 1986-91 (Box 1)
    - Bessie, Connie, undated (Box 1)
    - Blagg, Max, 1971-83 (Box 1)
    - Blyth, Charles, 1966-70 (Box 1)
    - Boice, Bruce, undated (Box 1)
    - Botstein, Leon, 1994-97 (Box 1)
    - Bourgeois, Jean-Louis, undated (Box 1)
    - Bouvier, Geof, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Braider, Donald, 1966-80 (Box 1)
    - Brainard, Joe, 1973-93 (Box 1)
    - Brown, Lee Ann, 1990-96 (Box 1)
    - Carlebach, Priscilla Wardwell, 1962-83 (Box 1)
    - Carlebach, William, 1971-72 (Box 1)
    - Carlebach, Michael, 1972-86 (Box 1)
    - Carruth, Hayden, 1980-83 (Box 1)
    - Chadwick, Cydney, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Chase, Louisa, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Chernoff, Maxine, 1989-93 (Box 1)
    - Cole, Norma, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Conarroe, Joe, 1986 (Box 1)
    - "Conjunctions" Magazine, 1983-92 (Box 1)
    - Conley, Brian, 1980-87 (Box 1)
    - Conley, Haven, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Corbett, William, 1985-95 (Box 1)
    - Costello, Bonnie, 1987-88 (Box 1)
    - Damrosch, Barbara, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Davidson, Don, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Davis, Jordan, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Davis, Jordan, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Davis, Lydia, 1991-95 (Box 1)
    - Day, Russell, 1996 (Box 1)
    - DeBoer, Frederik "Fritz", 1969-71 (Box 1)
    - DeLillo, Don, 1994-98 (Box 1)
    - Doris, Stacy, 1985-97; 2 (Box 1)
    - Ducornet, Rikki, 1995-98 (Box 1)
    - Dowell, Coleman, 1983-95 (Box 1)
    - DuPlessis, Rachel Blau, 1993-97 (Box 1)
    - Dumm, Thomas, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Elmslie, Kenward, 1973-99; 3 (Box 1)
    - Equi, Elaine, 1995-98 (Box 1)
    - Evans, Steve, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Fallaux, Emile, 1976-86 (Box 1)
    - Foer, Jonathan Safran, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Foster, Ed, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Fourcade, Dominique, 1991-92 (Box 1)
    - Fraser, Kathleen, 1992-97 (Box 1)
    - Gablik, Suzi, 1970-91 (Box 1)
    - Galassi, Jonathan, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Gallagher, Eliza, 1991-96 (Box 1)
    - Gander, Forrest, 1991-98 (Box 2)
    - Gizzi, Peter, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Gould, Henry, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Graham, Jorie, undated (Box 2)
    - Graham, Nan, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Groover, Jan, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Guest, Barbara, 1979-99 (Box 2)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1986-97 (Box 2)
    - Gurganus, Allan, 1983-93 (Box 2)
    - Hamilton, Richard, 1973-85; 2 (Box 2)
    - Hellman, Lillian, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Hillman, Brenda, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Hoover, Paul, 1989-95 (Box 2)
    - Howe, Susan, 1977-95 (Box 2)
    - Israel, David, 1992-94 (Box 2)
    - Jassaud, Gervais, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Joris, Pierre, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Kaine, Constance, 1977-92 (Box 2)
    - Kalleberg, Garrett, 1993-96; 2 (Box 2)
    - Keelan, Claudia, 1991-97 (Box 2)
    - Kelly, Robert, 1989-97 (Box 2)
    - Kermani, David, 1973-98 (Box 2)
    - Killian, Kevin, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Kleinzahler, August, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Knauth, Percy, 1963-94 (Box 2)
    - Knight, Pamela, undated (Box 2)
    - Knowlton, Win, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Koch, Kenneth, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Koo, Carolyn, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Kovac, Deirdré, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Lardner, Kate and James, 1958-81 (Box 2)
    - Lauterbach, Ann, undated (Box 2)
    - Lauterbach, Andree Fontaine (sister-in-law), 1966-99 (Box 2)
    - Lauterbach, David (brother), 1969-97 (Box 2)
    - Lauterbach, Elizabeth (mother), [ca. 1926-40]; 14 (Box 2)
    - Lauterbach, Hazel (grandmother), 1964-71 (Box 2)
    - Lauterbach, Jennifer (sister), [ca. 1967-77]; 2 (Box 3)
    - Lauterbach, Richard (father), [ca. 1949-50]; 7 (Box 3)
    - Book cover for "These are the Russians," by Richard Lauterbach, undated (Box 3)
    - Journal of Richard Lauterbach, undated (Box 3)
    - Lehman, David, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Leonardi, Hector, 1982-88 (Box 3)
    - Linford, Gary, 1973-97 (Box 3)
    - Lopate, Philip, 1974-87 (Box 3)
    - Louw, Roelof, undated (Box 3)
    - Machlin, Dan, 1995-88 (Box 3)
    - Mandel, Tom, 1991-92 (Box 3)
    - Matthews, Harry, 1970-79 (Box 3)
    - Messerli, Douglas, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Michener, Diana, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Minichello, Peter, undated (Box 3)
    - Unidentified found in correspondence (unsorted), undated (Box 3)
    - Molesworth, Charles, 1984-98 (Box 3)
    - Monroe, Jonathan, 1996 (Box 3)
    - Moody, Rick, 1997-98 (Box 3)
    - Morrow, Bradford, 1982-94 (Box 3)
    - Mounkhall, Stephen, undated (Box 3)
    - Nelson, Gale, 1996-97 (Box 3)
    - Neurath, Thomas, undated (Box 3)
    - Neighbors, Jennie, 1995-96 (Box 3)
    - North, Charles, 1996 (Box 3)
    - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Osman, Jena, 1991-97 (Box 3)
    - Padgett, Ron, 1994-97 (Box 3)
    - Palmer, Michael, 1982-97 (Box 3)
    - Perelman, Bob, 1996 (Box 3)
    - Perloff, Marjorie, 1976-98 (Box 3)
    - Phelan, Ellen, 1981-97 (Box 3)
    - Pratt, J. E. (Jim E.), 1964 (Box 3)
    - Potts, Randall, 1990-93 (Box 3)
    - Pozzi, Lucio, 1989-91 (Box 3)
    - Prideaux, Tom, 1982-94 (Box 3)
    - Songs by Tom Prideaux, undated (Box 3)
    - Rackin, Ethel, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Ramke, Bin, 1992-97 (Box 3)
    - Ramsdell, Heather, 1993-98 (Box 3)
    - Raworth, Tom, 1986-97 (Box 3)
    - Retallack, Joan, 1996-97 (Box 3)
    - Revell, Donald, 1989-97 (Box 3)
    - Richardson, Joan, 1989-93 (Box 3)
    - Richman, Sidney, undated (Box 3)
    - Robbins, Jack, undated (Box 4)
    - Robbins, Richard, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Robinson, Kit, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Rohrbach, Erica, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Rosenwasser, Rena, 1995-97 (Box 4)
    - Rubin, Elizabeth, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Rudeen, Ken, undated (Box 4)
    - Russell, John, 1972-85 (Box 4)
    - Rutkowski, Thaddeus, 1987-97 (Box 4)
    - Ryder, Neil, 1969-90 (Box 4)
    - St. John, David, undated (Box 4)
    - Scalapino, Leslie, 1984-96 (Box 4)
    - Schell, Jonathan, 1994-97 (Box 4)
    - Schneemann, Carolee, 1971-82 (Box 4)
    - Scholder, David, 1967-87 (Box 4)
    - Schwartz, Leonard, 1990-94 (Box 4)
    - Shapiro, David, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Shepherd, Reginald, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Sherry, James, 1995 (Box 4)
    - Silliman, Ronald, 1995-96 (Box 4)
    - Simpson, David, 1963-96 (Box 4)
    - Sloan, Mary Margaret, 1993-98 (Box 4)
    - Slovak, Paul, 1994 (Box 4)
    - Spahr, Juliana, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Stallybrass, Oliver, 1969-77 (Box 4)
    - Stickney, Walt-Christopher, 1970 (Box 4)
    - Straub, Peter, 1969-99; 6 (Box 4)
    - Straub, Roger, 1977-78 (Box 4)
    - Tillman, Lynne, 1973-97 (Box 4)
    - Trip, Allie, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Trip, Nathaniel, 1984-85 (Box 4)
    - Truitt, Sam, 1994-96 (Box 4)
    - Twichell, Chase, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Underhill, Frederick, undated (Box 4)
    - Verdelle, A. J., 1994 (Box 4)
    - Violi, Paul, 1989 (Box 4)
    - Vogelsang, Arthur, 1988-98 (Box 4)
    - Waldman, Anne, [ca. 1980-96] (Box 4)
    - Warren, Jennifer, 1968 (Box 4)
    - Watten, Barrett, 1990-99 (Box 4)
    - Weiley, Susan, 1967-74 (Box 4)
    - Welish, Marjorie, 1975-84 (Box 4)
    - White, Theodore, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Wiener, Chet, 1988-92; 2 (Box 4)
    - Wilner, Joshua, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Wolf, Leslie, 1978-82 (Box 4)
    - Wright, C. D., 1993-96 (Box 4)
    - Yau, John, undated (Box 4)
    - Zimet, Paul, 1972-74 (Box 4)
    - More requests for work, undated (Box 4)
    - Requests for writing, undated (Box 4)
    - Requests-literary and business, undated (Box 4)
    - ICA (Box 4)
    - Unidentified correspondence, undated (Box 4)
    - Random emails, undated (Box 4)
    - Unknown (I don't know) correspondence, undated (Box 4)
    - Various correspondence, undated; 3 (Box 4)
    - Various correspondence, undated; 21 (Box 5)
    - Various correspondence and poems, undated; 21 (Box 6)
    - Larry, 1964-65 (Box 6)
    - Various postcards, undated; 15 (Box 7)
  - Poetry
    - Early poems, undated; 22 (Box 7)
    - Drafts of early poems, undated (Box 7)
    - "Where was is" drafts, undated (Box 7)
    - "Softly Loudly" the Whitechapel, "Phases," poetry, undated (Box 7)
    - Early poems, undated; 15 (Box 8)
    - "Greeks," proof, undated
    - "Greeks"
      - Book one paste-ups, undated (Box 8)
      - Book one Ann Lauterbach, 1970s (Box 8)
      - Book one drafts, undated (Box 8)
    - "Many Times, But Then," Univ. of Texas Press Poetry Series, 1979 (Box 8)
    - Drafts of "Chalk", undated; 3 (Box 8)
    - "Many Times, But Then," drafts, undated (Box 8)
    - "Chalk", undated (Box 8)
    - Drafts of "MTBT" and "Book One," and "Ideas of the Actual", undated (Box 8)
    - AL's drafts of poems, undated (Box 8)
    - Drafts "MTBT", undated (Box 8)
    - Proof of "Many Times, But Then", 1978 (Box 8)
    - Various poems, undated; 12 (Box 9)
    - "Sacred Weather" drafts, undated (Box 9)
    - "Before Recollection" drafts, undated; 6 (Box 9)
    - Various drafts, undated; 2 (Box 9)
    - Typescript for "Before Recollection", undated (Box 9)
    - Early poems-BR?, undated (Box 9)
    - Ramke, Bin, undated (Box 9)
    - "Before Recollection," Princeton UP New Jersey, 1987 (Box 9)
    - "Clamor" by Ann Lauterbach, undated; 2 (Box 10)
    - "Waiting at the Table", undated (Box 10)
    - Various drafts, undated; 4 (Box 10)
    - "Clamor," author's copy, undated (Box 10)
    - "Clamor" photocopies, undated (Box 10)
    - Drafts: "And for Example", undated; 14 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence: "And for Example," Courtney Hodell, 1994 (Box 10)
    - "And for Example," Penguin. New York, 1994 (Box 10)
    - Various drafts, undated (Box 11)
    - Drafts of poetry 1998-1999, 1998-99 (Box 11)
    - "On a Stair" drafts, 1994-95; 2 (Box 11)
    - "A Clown" drafts, undated (Box 11)
    - "And for Example" drafts and more, undated (Box 11)
    - "A Clown, Some Colors, A Doll, Her Stories, A Song, a Moonlit Cove," with letters, 1994 (Box 11)
    - "On a Stair" drafts, 1995 (Box 11)
    - "On a Stair" drafts with notes, 1996; 2 (Box 11)
    - "On a Stair" drafts (Bramble portrait), undated (Box 11)
    - "On a Stair" drafts, undated; 4 (Box 11)
    - "W/est" drafts, undated (Box 11)
    - "On a Stair" galley, 1997; 2 (Box 11)
    - "On a Stair" galley book with author's corrections, undated (Box 11)
    - "On a Stair" correspondence, Courtney Hodell, undated (Box 11)
    - "On a Stair" galley, Penguin, 1997 (Box 11)
    - "On a Stair" photocopies, undated; 4 (Box 11)
    - MacArthur correspondence, 1993 (Box 11)
    - "Later that Evening," pub. Jordan Davis, NY (Box 11)
    - "Sacred Weather", 1984 (Box 11)
    - "Edward Hoppen's Way", undated (Box 11)
    - "N/est" "Bomb", undated (Box 11)
    - "A Clown, some colors, doll, her stories, a song, a moonlit cove" with Ellen Phelan, undated (Box 11)
    - "Thripsis", undated (Box 11)
    - Poetry projects with others, undated (Box 11)
    - Various drafts, undated; 10 (Box 12)
    - Early poems, undated; 3 (Box 12)
    - Various poems, undated; 3 (Box 12)
    - Three poems--"Use," "a Rose," "Chase", undated (Box 12)
    - Poems from friends, undated (Box 12)
    - Poems left unfinished, undated; 2 (Box 12)
  - Prose
    - Extra copies of essays, typescripts, undated (Box 13)
    - Various essays/drafts, undated; 4 (Box 13)
    - Ann's essays--West magazine, "Use this word in a sentence," poems, undated (Box 13)
    - Essays, talks, and class notes, undated (Box 13)
    - Various essays, "Found Credo," "Pragmatic Example", undated (Box 13)
    - "Night Sky," drafts, 1996; 10 (Box 13)
    - Notes/Essays, 1997; 2 (Box 13)
    - Win Knowlton, undated (Box 13)
    - "Credo", undated (Box 13)
    - "Chase", undated (Box 13)
    - Drafts of "Lines written to Bob Perelman in the margins of Marginalization of Poetry", undated (Box 13)
    - "Eve", 1995 (Box 13)
    - Walt Whitman, undated; 2 (Box 13)
    - "Pragmatic Example," "How I think about what I write" (Box 13)
    - Memoirs, undated (Box 13)
    - "Poetry as Value", undated (Box 13)
    - "Value as Poetry" drafts, 1994; 2 (Box 13)
    - "Unpicturing Fair Realism" drafts and galleys, undated (Box 13)
    - "All Poetry is Contemporary Poetry" drafts, 1994 (Box 13)
    - About Joe Brainard, 1993; 2 (Box 13)
    - Memoirs of Stuyvesant's Folly, English class work, stories, essays, undated (Box 13)
    - Literary sentiment, undated (Box 13)
    - Bendell/Lauterbach interview, undated (Box 14)
    - Panel 4/27/96, D.C. conference, 1996 (Box 14)
    - Various prose drafts, undated (Box 14)
    - Book catalogues, undated (Box 14)
    - Various notes, undated (Box 14)
    - Charles Altieri, "Jorie Graham and Ann Lauterbach: Towards a Contemporary Poetics of Eloquence" Cream City review, 1988 (Box 14)
    - Charles Altieri, "Ann Lauterbach's Still," Wallace Stevens Journal, 1995 (Box 14)
    - Thomas Fink, "Desedimenting Racial and Gendered", undated (Box 14)
    - Garrett Kalleberg, "A Form of Duration: On Ann Lauterbach's 'And for Example,'" Denver Quarterly, 1995 (Box 14)
    - James McCorkle DLB 193 "Ann Lauterbach", 1998 (Box 14)
    - Unpublished essays about AL, undated (Box 14)
    - "River Decisions," AL at C.U.N.Y., Bobbelmann, Duncan, undated (Box 14)
    - Unpublished essays on AL--Anne Shaw, Gweneth Catlin, Steven Mounkhall, undated (Box 14)
    - "Clamor" review, American Poetry Review, 1988 (Box 14)
    - Janet Bowdan, "Diverse strangers flower and diverge, and when they cross paths three strangers flower and are clairvoyant: Three Reviews", review of "Clamor", undated (Box 14)
    - William Corbett, "Scrapple from the Apple: A Charlie Parker tune," Harvard review, 1995 (Box 14)
    - Review of "Clamor," Joseph Donahue (Box 14)
    - Review of "Many Times, But then", 1980 (Box 14)
    - Elizabeth Gunderson, "Ann Lauterbach", 1995 (Box 14)
    - Bonnie Costello, "Parnassus: Poetry in review", 1980 (Box 14)
    - Scott Ferguson, "Ann Lauterbach: An Advance", 1988 (Box 14)
    - "On a Stair," review, Regan Good, 1997 (Box 14)
    - "On a Stair," review, S.P. Healey, 1997 (Box 14)
    - Krysia Jopek, "Prepositional Investigations of Language and Poetry", undated (Box 14)
    - Myra Junyk, review of "Before Recollection", 1989 (Box 14)
    - "Missing Her," review of "Clamor," Claudia Keelan, 1993 (Box 14)
    - "Canon, Temple, Living within the Pause," review of "And for Example," Claudia Keelan, 1996 (Box 14)
    - Review of "On a Stair," Andrew McCarron, 1997 (Box 14)
    - "Eternal Questions, Unmatched Beauty," review of "On a Stair," Dionisio Martinez, undated (Box 14)
    - "Stair Master: AL Traces the Mind in Motion," John Olson, undated (Box 14)
    - "Review of "On a Stair," Andrew Osborn, undated (Box 14)
    - Review of all books by AL, 1995-96 (Box 14)
    - Forecasts, "And for Example," review, 1994 (Box 14)
    - Donald Revell, "Rose as Decoy, Beauty as Use: Mark Rudman, David St. John, AL", undated (Box 14)
    - Donald Revell, "The Plural of Vision Remains Vision:...AL", undated (Box 14)
    - Leonard Schwartz, "La Crete du Neuf: Nouvelle Poesie Americaine", 1994 (Box 14)
    - "Process and Movement," review of "Clamor," Juliana Spahr, undated (Box 14)
    - Henry Taylor, "Ordinary Words, Extraordinary meanings: 3 Poets", 1995 (Box 14)
    - "On a Stair" review, Chris Tysh, 1998 (Box 14)
    - "Spoken Words: The Spaces Between the World and its Telling," Syd M., 1994 (Box 14)
    - "Poetic Friction: ...AL..." Karen Volkman, 1998 (Box 14)
    - "And for Example: AL", 1994 (Box 14)
    - Stephen Yenser review, 1994 (Box 14)
    - "Sound and Sense: Review of Clamor," Nicholas Christopher and Harriet Zinnes, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Portland Review, "Many Times, But Then", undated (Box 14)
    - "Night Sky I", undated (Box 14)
    - Intro to "Wuthering Heights", 1978 (Box 14)
    - "Links w/out Links: The Voice of the Turtle", 1992 (Box 14)
    - "20 Oct 1994: Joe Brainard", 1994-95 (Box 14)
    - "A Life in Soho, When Even its Name was New" AL essay, 1996 (Box 14)
    - "Inventing Unreality", 1998 (Box 14)
    - "Is I Another? A Talk in 7 Beginnings", 1989 (Box 14)
    - "Slaves of Fashion" response to Harold Bloom, 1998 (Box 14)
    - "Lines written to Bob Perelman in the margins of 'The Marginalization of Poetry'", undated (Box 14)
    - "Louisa Chase: Figure in a Landscape", undated (Box 14)
    - "Fifth Season," published version, undated (Box 14)
    - Barbara Guest, American letters and commentary, "Unpicturing fair realism", undated (Box 14)
    - Genesis, "Communion: Contemporary writers reveal the Bible in their lives", undated (Box 14)
    - "What is the grass: Notes leading up to and away from W. Whitman", undated (Box 14)
    - "On Memory", undated (Box 14)
    - "Found Credo", undated (Box 14)
    - "Fifteen ways of preparing to think about language as place in urban poetics", undated (Box 14)
    - Hasan, 1998 (Box 14)
    - "On flaws: towards a poetics of the whole fragment", 1999 (Box 14)
    - "AL: An Interview with Molly Bendall", 1992 (Box 14)
    - "Interview with AL", 1993 (Box 14)
    - Denver Quarterly interview, 1995 (Box 14)
    - "At the Guggenheim with AL", 1996 (Box 14)
    - Conversation between Heather Ramsdell and AL, undated (Box 14)
    - "Genius in Exile," Interview with Joseph Vogue, undated (Box 14)
    - Interview with Sydney Janis, undated (Box 14)
    - "Misquotations from Reality", 1996 (Box 14)
    - "Party, community, movement: a conversation: ....AL...", 1996 (Box 14)
    - Introduction for Marjorie Welish, 1997 (Box 14)
    - Introduction of AL by Beth Anderson, 1994 (Box 14)
    - Intro of and by AL in D.C., 1996 (Box 14)
    - Intro for Susan Howe at DIA, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Intro of AL, undated (Box 14)
    - Intro for Don Delillo, undated (Box 14)
    - Blurbs, undated (Box 14)
    - "Subject to Change", 1997 (Box 14)
    - Art reviews--Donal Sultan and Joel Shapiro, undated (Box 14)
    - Drafts of prose (novel), undated (Box 14)
    - "These Days," drafts, undated; 2 (Box 14)
  - Journals
    - Journals and yearly planners, 1962-78; 19 (Box 15)
    - Journals and yearly planners, 1978-91; 27 (Box 16)
    - Journals and yearly planners, 1992-94 undated; 23 (Box 17)
  - Early Writing